Thank you.
The band...
Mommy, please don't go.
Don't worry, Gerda.
I'll be back soon.
Stay and make sure Daddy plays
all the right notes, okay?
Goodbye. I love you.
All right, gentlemen?
It's all right, sultan.
Nothing to fear, just
a little wind.
It's all right.
Amy?
Amy!
We'll have to give up
the search for tonight,
otherwise, someone else
is going to be lost.
No, no.
I'll not
leave her here.
Go home!
Take the child with you.
Everybody go home.
I'll not
leave her here.
Oh, Gerda.
Oh...
Thank you.
Come on—
let's get you inside
and get you warm.
Thank you for all
your help, gentlemen.
Of course.
I'm sure Wolfgang
will find her.
Yes, he will.
Amy!
Amy...
Mommy?
Mommy? Mommy!
Amy!
Mommy?
Good night, Daddy.
Good morning, Daddy.
Kai, your hours
will be from dawn
until the last guest
goes to bed.
If my guests decide
to stay up all night,
so shall you.
When I summon you,
you will be here
before this bell...
stops ringing,
no matter where you are,
no matter what you are doing.
You understand?
Yes, sir.
Kai,
tardiness in any shape or form
will not be tolerated.
Do you understand?
I understand, sir.
I thought you'd
be here yesterday.
Oh, well, I... had
no money for the coach, sir,
so I had to walk
over the mountains.
Why are you
smiling?
Just pleased
to be here, sir.
Bellboy...
Bellboy!
Good day, sir.
I'm Kai.
Yes, I know.
Not acceptable...
Not in the white bear hotel.
Do it the proper way.
Yes, Mr. Hahn.
Oh, hello.
Look at those.
Aren't they beautiful?
They're gorgeous.
Why don't you
buy them?
Oh, I don't
need them.
I was just
admiring them.
It's the first snow.
Hope it settles.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
I just hate winter,
that's all.
Pretzels!
Hot pretzels!
I think
she likes you.
I, uh...
It's all right, Kai.
You and Gerda would make
a splendid couple.
Well, tell
her father that.
Oh, he'll come around.
He's been unhappy for so long,
he's bound to sooner or later.
Minna, why is it that Gerda
hates the winter so much?
It took her mother's life
and her father's joy
all in one night.
What are you going to do
for your 18th birthday?
Your father would let you
have a party, you know,
if you asked him.
Do you think so?
I'll tell him
he has to.
It's been far too long
since we had a party here.
And you can invite
your boyfriend.
He's not my boyfriend.
Your mother
used to look at me like that...
And she couldn't lie
about her feelings either.
Did I put pepper in this
already?
Twice, at least.
Oh...
Gerda, why don't you wear
your mother's rose brooch?
She'd want you to.
Do you remember
how it was always
warm to the touch
when you were a child?
She made it magic.
I know why it was warm.
She used to put it on the stove
before she kissed me good night.
No— it was magic.
And it's not meant
to sit in a drawer.
So how are you
liking it here, Kai?
Well, let me see.
Apart from 20-hour workdays,
the endless lifting
of heavy luggage,
the chopping
of rock-hard firewood,
the hauling
of heavy laundry,
and, of course, the cleaning
of endless muddy boots,
I like it just fine.
Sounds like
he's coming this way.
You'd better scoot.
Where's that bellboy?
Kai!
Minna, have you seen
the bellboy?
The guests are asking
for their boots.
No, I haven't
seen him lately,
though I expect
the boots will be here
soon enough, nice and clean.
Minna, you should
check that stew.
It does not smell
up to your usual standard.
Likely just needs
a little bit of seasoning.
I'll see to it.
Wolfgang...
Hmm?
You know,
he's not a bad boy.
Meaning?
Haven't you seen the way
he and Gerda look at each other?
And why shouldn't he?
He's a nice young man,
and she's
a most attractive girl.
She's a...
Young woman.
Bellboy.
Yes, sir?
What do you know
about that?
Uh, nothing, sir.
No.
No!
Uh, Gerda...
Listen, do you want
to come skating with me
after work tonight?
No.
I'm not really
any good.
Well, I could
teach you.
I don't skate anymore.
Why not?
I told you,
I don't like winter.
There you are,
winter's finished.
So if I step outside,
there'll be daffodils everywhere
and all the snow
will be gone?
Didn't you
promise me daffodils?
Oh, they're out there.
They're just...
Just a little shy,
that's all.
Maybe if you come
skating with me,
they'll come out.
I'm warning you,
I'm not very good.
I haven't been
on skates in years.
You'll be fine.
Come on, try it.
It's easy.
Come on.
Hey, maybe one little spin
is all it will take
for the daffodils
to come up.
Oh, well,
if the daffodils insist...
Are you all right?
I'm fine.
I'm so sorry.
It was my fault.
Really, Kai,
it's all right.
I just don't want to do
any more spins.
Okay, agreed, then,
no more spins.
are you all right?
I think so.
you know, for someone
who can't skate,
you were pretty
impressive...
And the prettiest girl
on the whole lake.
I was the only girl
Which, I'd like
to point out,
was entirely devoid
of daffodils.
They're still just a little
uncertain about you, that's all.
Although...
Bellboy!
I'm right here.
Don't make me
go backwards.
I'm going to get
some chestnuts.
That's fine.
Thank you.
What?
Gerda,
I just...
Duck!
You were saying?
Well, I was
about to say
I think you should
give winter a second chance,
although now
I'm not so sure.
I bet you used to do this a lot
with all the other girls
on the other side
of the mountain.
I did...
But they were
my sisters.
My parents died
when I was quite young,
so it was up to me
to entertain my sisters.
Your sisters
were very lucky.
Listen, I know
your father doesn't think
I'm good enough
for you, but...
I love you, Gerda.
I...
We'd better get back.
It's just snow.
It can't hurt us.
Kai? Kai!
Kai, are you all right?
I've got something
in my eye.
Let me see it.
It's fine.
It's gone now.
Let me look.
It's all bloodshot.
Leave me alone!
I'm not a baby.
Sorry, it just...
It just stings, that's all.
It's gone now. I'm fine.
It was just a piece of ice.
All right, I think
you should go on alone now.
What?
I'm just
thinking of you.
You don't want to have
to explain to your father
when he sees us
together, do you?
But, Kai—
just go on
ahead of me.
It's for the best.
Go on.
If you think so...
What happened?
Mischief makers,
I suppose.
Kai, the other night
at the lake.
I...
I'm sorry, Gerda.
I don't know what happened.
I just...
It's all right.
You don't need
to apologize.
Maybe we can
go again tonight.
I could use
another lesson
from a certain handsome
instructor I know.
Well, he'd better be
a skilled teacher,
because, frankly,
your skating is hopeless
and graceless.
Amazing things,
snowflakes.
There isn't a fault in them.
They're perfect.
If only
they didn't melt.
Why don't you close the window?
It's freezing.
Have you ever
been cut?
What?
With something
really sharp, like...
Like a knife,
like a blade,
like a horrible
piece of ice?
Have you ever been cut?
I don't know
who you are anymore, Kai.
What happened?
I don't know
what I've done wrong.
What have I done
to make him dislike me?
Ask him.
Why have you
become like this?
Why are you
being so horrible?
It's as if you're determined
to turn everyone against you.
They're already
against me.
Your father
treats me like a slave.
He respects you.
I know he does.
Yeah, and one day,
he's going to let me
run the hotel, right?
I don't think so.
It's not like that.
Maybe if you were to stick
to the job...
Hey, Gerda,
I have an idea.
Why don't we follow
the mountains up north,
just you and me,
skating and skating
and skating.
Would you like that?
We could go right now.
We won't tell anybody.
Let's go!
No. I want you
to come back
to the hotel with me
before you get sacked.
Kai...
I don't understand.
You said you loved me.
You never said
you loved me.
Madame...
Good afternoon.
I do apologize.
We weren't expecting
anyone today.
Do you mind
if I ask you
how you made it through
the pass to the village?
The roads have been
closed for days.
Would you be so kind as to have
someone fetch my bags?
They're outside.
Ja, ja.
Bellboy?
Bellboy! Bellboy!
Now, would it be possible for me
to have a room on the top floor?
Ja, the top floor.
How long will you be
staying with us, madame?
Why? Are you expecting
a rush of late-arriving guests?
No.
The storm may continue
for another day.
I thought that perhaps you might
be more comfortable in a suite.
The storm will be
gone tomorrow.
Trust me.
Would you like me to have
some hot tea sent to your room?
No, no tea.
Just a jug of ice water.
I'll have it sent
straight up.
Bellboy!
He's somewhere.
Kai?
Are you going to stand outside
for the rest of your life?
Do you like mirrors?
I was just wondering
whether you knew or not...
And you don't, do you?
What are you doing?
I'm lighting a fire for you.
It's freezing.
Do you think
I'm cold?
Do I look cold
to you?
I'm not cold.
I'm not cold at all.
You've got
lovely eyes.
It's the first thing
I noticed about you.
How old are you?
18.
I think I'm needed
downstairs.
About a month ago,
there was a terrible
snowstorm here.
It was just like today.
It was a blizzard.
Do you know anyone
who was...
How can I put this?
Affected by it?
Anyone who changed?
I don't know
what you mean.
For instance,
have you noticed
what a mean, selfish
little person
you've become
recently?
You know
why that is?
No.
Because you want
something from me.
You crave it
more than anything else.
In fact, you can't
stop thinking about it...
Even though you don't know
what it is.
I'll be on the lake
tonight.
Why don't you come down
and see me?
I can't tonight.
Oh.
What a pity.
I'm only here
for one night.
You like winter,
don't you?
Kai,
come here.
I've got something
for you.
Aren't you even going
to wish me a happy birthday?
I'm sorry.
Yes, Gerda, happy birthday.
Thank you.
I've been awful, I know,
but that's finished.
Forgive me, Gerda.
I've just...
I've been sick, that's all.
Just sick.
Then you'll be
at my party tonight?
Don't let me down.
Daddy didn't want you there
after the way you've been.
I'll be there,
I promise.
I'll never forgive you
if you don't turn up.
I mean it, Kai.
I promise.
Wow, look at it.
It's beautiful.
I'm getting in.
You know you want to.
You know
you want to come.
Look at that.
Oh, it goes so fast.
This is neat.
Wow.
Let's get out of here.
I didn't want you
to see my new dress yet.
What do you think?
You're not ready.
And what do you
have your skates for?
Gerda, will you just keep these
for me till tomorrow?
Why?
Please, just do it.
I'll see you downstairs
in five minutes.
There she is.
Happy birthday, Gerda.
Doesn't she
look lovely?
He'll be here.
He promised.
I've got
what you want, Kai.
Make a wish.
Kai...
Forget him.
Something must be wrong.
I have to go look for him.
Gerda, he's a foolish,
selfish boy.
You deserve better.
You don't know him at all.
None of you do.
Gerda...
No. Let her go.
Hey, here,
let me have your sled.
No.
Just give it to me.
No, I'm playing with it.
Take me with you.
Faster!
How fast would you
like to go?
As fast as you can go.
Faster!
I think
I've broken my arm.
I don't think so.
You know I told you
you wanted something from me,
but you didn't know
what it was?
This is what it was.
It's all right, Kai.
You can hold on to me.
See, they love the winter.
They embrace it.
And up here,
they fear the winter,
huddle away from it.
Shall we teach them
a lesson?
I think we shall.
Isn't it marvelous?
Doesn't it make your blood
just run cold with joy?
I can't believe
you just did that.
I can do anything I want.
That's the whole point.
Slow down, girls.
He always was
a reckless boy.
You keep taking chances,
you pay the price in the end.
That's the truth.
That's the cold, hard truth.
He didn't die.
I know it.
He was with that woman.
Somehow, she took him.
Woman?
What woman?
She stayed here
the night he disappeared.
No, the pass was closed.
We didn't have any guests.
I know how much
you miss him,
but you must face the fact
that he is dead,
and I know it doesn't
seem like it now,
but you will come
to accept it over time.
Like you did?
Minna, when I talk
to my father
about Kai's
disappearance,
I can see something
hidden deep in his eyes,
something he's
not telling me.
I think you know
what it is.
It's just that there have been
a lot of very unusual things
going on in recent years,
unexplained things.
You mean
like my mother's death?
Yes, and many others,
who just... Disappeared.
But, you know, maybe it's best
we don't talk about this.
No, minna.
You have to tell me.
Who were the people
who disappeared?
Young men, mostly, boys,
from villages
all across the valley
and beyond,
most of them disappearing
without a trace.
But how?
Why?
Well, some think
they were taken, abducted.
By whom?
Tell me.
The Snow Queen.
You mean winter?
No.
Winter is merely
the Snow Queen's...
Pet.
But it's all
just a myth, child.
Please promise me
you won't concern yourself
with it.
Brothers and sisters
in Christ,
this morning we're gathered
to honor and remember
the life of brother Kai
and to celebrate the promise
of his sure resurrection.
The Lord is my Shepherd...
He makes me lie down
in green pastures.
He leads me
beside quiet waters.
He guides me in the paths
of righteousness for his
name's sake...
Let me have him back.
I'll give you my beautiful boots
if you let me have him back.
I'll give you myself
for Kai.
Come back,
little girl.
You don't want to go yet.
You don't want to go.
You're not dead, my little girl.
No, no, no.
You are just full of water
inside of you.
Come on, spit it out.
Come back.
Come back!
What were you doing
in the water?
I threw myself in.
Good thing I was
expecting you.
Your boots arrived
a few minutes ago.
Help yourself
to the strawberries.
Watch out
for the juice, though.
Remember
the last time,
you couldn't get them
out of your dress?
Threw yourself in,
did you?
One of those quiet,
obedient girls
who doesn't say anything
until she screams.
Oh, the world's
full of them.
"Sleepy girls,"
I call them.
Sleepy girls...
That when someone
combs your hair,
you get sleepy?
I can't stay here.
I'm looking for someone.
Lovely hair you've got.
It's so long,
and you must be
so tired.
Beautiful...
Lovely,
sleepy hair.
Dropping off.
Very sleepy now.
I can't stay here.
I'm looking
for someone.
Kai— have you
seen him?
Please tell me
you've seen him.
Kai, Kai, I'm sure
he'll pop by.
In a minute, you'll decide
you want to go to sleep.
I don't know
where he is,
but I set off
to find him
because I couldn't stand
doing nothing.
Up to bed, then.
There's a good girl.
No, I must go on.
You must go back
before you can go on.
No.
Thank you
for rescuing me,
but I have
to find Kai.
I can't stay here.
As you wish.
It was nice of you
to stop by, anyway.
Quite nice of me
to save your life, as well.
You worry too much,
sleepy girl,
who takes the weight
of the whole world
on her shoulders,
trying to grow up
too soon.
How's the bed?
Is it by any chance
the softest bed
you've ever been in?
It's...
It's indescribable.
Didn't have any
bedtime stories
when we were
a little girl, did we?
My poor old sausage.
I'll make up for that,
I promise you.
Gerda... Gerda.
Gerda, listen,
roses?
Is it that time
of year already?
They remind me
of something, someone.
Do they make you think
of a boy?
Gerda...
Kai needs you.
We can help you find him.
We know where he is.
I think he needed help.
He needed someone to...
Get out of here.
Oh, it's so hard
to remember.
You need to stop
trying so hard,
don't you?
Yes, I suppose I do.
Now, go to sleep,
my sweetheart,
just like mommy says.
Gerda?
Gerda,
time to get up.
Wolfgang!
Lovely girl.
Such a lovely girl,
and you're such
lovely company.
That's why I like you
so much.
You're kind
and considerate,
and you really help
around the house.
You are a joy
to have around, really.
Look at you smiling.
You had to grow up
too soon, didn't you?
It must have been awful.
Yes, it was.
You know the best time
in your life?
It's when you're young
and you've got someone
to take care of you
night and day.
It's what I call
"the spring of life."
So you're up.
Where am I?
Where does it look
like you are?
You're home, right down
to the last detail.
How long have I
been asleep?
I don't know.
I was away on business.
A couple of months.
Months?
I'm home now,
home for the summer.
I did my work
for the year.
I can't stay here.
It's too cold.
Poor Kai.
All change involves pain.
You don't understand.
If I stay here,
I'm going to freeze to death.
Well, then,
I suppose you'll die.
I want a fire.
Just let me get some—
no fire!
No fire!
I hate fire.
Kai,
answer me
one question.
Have you ever
in your whole life
ever felt anything like
that first kiss I gave you?
No.
No, you haven't.
This...
This was once
the most beautiful mirror
in the world.
I'm sure an intelligent boy
like you
could put it back together
quite easily.
Once you've put it
back together,
then you can go...
If you still want to.
I'm not going to do
anything you say,
and I'm certainly
not going to touch
some stupid glass jigsaw.
You want to know
what real cold is?
Real cold
will kill you dead,
just like that.
Stop it, please.
You're to stay
on the ground floor.
I'm a very
light sleeper,
and if you wake me up
during the summer,
I'll make you suffer.
I kissed you once,
and you slept
for two months.
Think about that,
because one kiss
won't last forever.
Sooner or later,
you're going to be
coming to me,
begging me
for a second kiss.
Why should I want
to kiss you again?
I don't want
anything from you.
That's what they all say...
To start with.
I won't stay here.
You're perfectly free
to leave, Kai,
as soon as you
find a way out.
Mommy, can I ask you
a question?
Of course.
When will I be old enough
to leave home?
Why would you want
What a horrible thing
to say.
I'm sorry.
I just meant—
no. No, no, no.
You've really spoiled my day.
You've really upset me.
Thank you so much
for ruining years of happiness
with one unnecessary comment.
Please tell me you're not
one of those selfish girls
who only thinks
about what she wants.
I'm sorry.
I know you're not
really asleep.
I'm not going to sit here
forever.
Somebody's coming
to look for me.
We're going to walk
out of here and go home.
What do you think
about that?
Afternoon nap for you,
my girl.
Sleepy girl,
if I'm not mistaken.
I was wondering...
How long have I
been here for?
What an extraordinary
question.
You've been here
all your life.
Sleepytime
for sleepy girls.
Time for
an afternoon nap.
Time to get
your beauty sleep.
There you go.
Off to bed.
Sleepy girl...
Gerda!
Oh, Wolfgang,
just let me catch my breath.
Come on, minna.
She must be here
somewhere.
She knows these woods.
Gerda!
All right.
Gerda... Gerda...
Over here.
Kai, you're here.
I know you're here.
Yes.
we can help you.
We know where he is.
Kai?
Kai is not here.
Is Kai dead?
No.
we've been in the earth,
where the dead are,
but Kai is not here.
He passed here months ago.
He was with the Snow Queen.
But where
have they gone?
They are nowhere.
She is winter,
and winter has passed.
Winter is elsewhere.
But she must have taken him
somewhere.
Where did she go?
To her great place
in the north,
if you want
to find Snow Queen,
you must pass
through each season
before you can reach her,
and unless you reach him
before the winter solstice,
Kai will die there, too.
No!
So you're going
to walk out
into the darkness of the forest
all on your own,
a little girl
with no food?
I'm not a little girl,
and I don't belong here.
You know that.
You can't keep me here.
Let me go.
You're right.
Why don't you just pop in,
I'll make
a picnic, and—
no.
If I go back in,
you will never let me out.
You'll see to that.
What are you going to do
when you find the Snow Queen?
You can't defeat her.
It's hopeless.
How do you know?
Because...
Because she's my sister.
It's true, Gerda,
and only I know
how truly cold and ruthless
she is at her core.
I've watched her
year after year
clawing
for more power.
Her arrogance
knows no bounds.
However hopeless it is,
I must find him.
But why?
Why is he worth it?
Because he made me
want to live again.
Remember
how I saved you?
Never underestimate
the power of a kiss.
Gerda!
No, no.
It's just a log,
Wolfgang.
It's only a log.
It's all right.
We'll find her.
I know in my heart
she's going to be fine.
I hope...
Since you seem to have
forgotten the hotel rules,
I'll run through
them for you.
Rule one, never disturb
a sleeping polar bear,
or you'll
get a smack.
Rule two, if a polar bear
is not sleeping,
he's almost
certainly fishing.
If you disturb
a fishing polar bear,
you will get a smack.
Rule three,
any attempts at escape
will result in a smack.
You got that, Sonny?
Absolutely.
Good.
You really hit me.
If I'd really hit you,
you'd be dead.
Help! Help!
Please to open the door...
Somebody...
Who's in there?
Hapless magician
needing urgent assistance.
But you're
not in there!
Definitely in here.
Box is disappearing-
type cabinet...
Hapless magician
inside.
Please knock
on all surfaces.
Harder!
Aha!
Endless thanks,
kind lady.
Chen at your
service.
My name's Gerda.
What are you doing here?
Making way to gorgeous palace
of Summer Princess
full of optimism
for post
of conjuring entertainer
for royal court.
Are you sure
you're ready for that?
You seem a little uncomfortable
with the practical side.
Chen therefore needing
beautiful and smart assistant.
Well, I hope
you find one.
No, no, no! Already found!
You she.
You help Chen get job
in summer palace.
I'd like to help you,
but I have to save Kai
from the Snow Queen
before
the winter solstice.
Ah, Kai...
From Snow Queen...
Do you know
where Snow Queen is?
Not exactly, but i'm
not going to stop looking
till I've found her.
Summer Princess will know.
Snow Queen...
Summer Princess...
Relations, got to be.
You help Chen find
Summer Princess
help you find Kai.
Good deal?
Hmm...
This is impossible.
Get back to work.
Don't you ever
want to get out of here?
Why should I?
This is
a very good fishing spot,
I have a nice, cold,
north-facing room,
and...
And?
And nothing.
Get back to work.
All right.
This is a very stupid
way to fish.
I can't believe
you ever caught anything.
I'm glad my father's
not here to see this.
Humph— four hours
without a fish.
Umm-umm-umm.
Oh what a waste...
And you are
looking for...?
The way out.
Why shouldn't I?
I don't want to be here.
You haven't finished
the puzzle yet.
I don't care about the puzzle.
I want to find Gerda.
Her majesty wants you
to finish the puzzle,
and I'm here
to make sure you do.
Don't you have
a will of your own?
Yes.
It's to do
whatever she wants.
What about what I want?
Not really important.
Ha ha!
Told you.
My way is better.
What are you
looking at?
Get back to work.
I've made you
a nice dinner.
Come, now, Wolfgang...
You really must eat.
It's your
favorite dish.
I...
I appreciate
what you are
trying to do, minna,
but I don't play...
Anymore.
Have you been traveling
a long way, Chen?
Oh, very far.
All available palaces,
all turning Chen down.
You must practice very hard
to become a good magician.
Problem
with practice,
Chen always
getting self stuck.
That's why young magician
so glad to find you.
Chen taking this place
by storm.
It looks very grand.
Kai...
Hello, Kai.
How are you
settling in?
Fine, thank you.
Well, that's
certainly progress,
considering
the last time we talked,
you were cold
and miserable,
and wanted nothing more
than to go home.
How are you getting on
with my mirror?
Quite well.
Do you call that
"doing well," Kai?
No, ma'am.
What was that?
I didn't quite hear you.
No, ma'am.
It's hard.
Hard?
Too difficult, Kai?
No.
I should have
tried harder.
Yes, you should.
So, how should
I punish you
for not trying
hard enough?
I'm not your prisoner.
Come here.
Don't make me
tell you again.
Does that hurt?
What do you think?
Does it hurt now?
No.
Have you
missed me, Kai?
I've missed you
terribly.
Have you thought
about me at all,
or has your mind
been on that girl?
Yes...
I mean, no.
I mean— I don't know
what I mean.
Your hand's
shaking.
Why's that?
I guess it's been
a while, hasn't it,
since I last
kissed you.
You'd better get busy
on that mirror, Kai,
because what you're
feeling now is nothing,
trust me.
Before long, you'll be
climbing those stairs,
desperate
for another kiss.
Couldn't we just
tell them we're here
and ask for
an audition?
Truth is, Chen already
auditioned at summer palace.
Thrown out two,
three times.
Only trying again
because of smart
and beautiful assistant.
When Summer Princess
comes down in the morning,
we are amazing her
before she's
throwing us out.
I'm not sure
how good of an idea
this is, Chen...
Are they ghosts?
No, no, just dreams.
Dreams?
Royal dreams.
None of our business.
Please help find
magic deck of cards.
Roses...
Roses,
talk to me about Kai.
Me...
That's me.
Intruders...
Intruders!
Not intruders!
Chinese magician,
and smart and beautiful
assistant.
You again.
This time
with complete new show,
all tricks at
highest perfection,
and best
available back-up.
We do audition now?
Grab the
intruders!
No! Entertainers,
for royal audition.
Royal audition,
my foot.
We've thrown you out
three times this summer!
You! It's you!
I'm very sorry, your highness.
I know we shouldn't be here,
but I was wondering
if you could tell me—
I've been dreaming about you
for months now!
What shall I do with them,
your highness?
Do with them?
Why, give them
everything they want.
Including the conjurer,
your highness?
Oh, yes, he's been
very helpful.
Then the conjurer too.
You will not regretting this,
your highness.
Chen soon delighting court
with all his tricks.
Nosy boys tend not to live
too long around here.
Best news ever!
Princess letting Chen do
magic show without audition,
thanks to you.
Chen, that's wonderful,
she has promised to tell the way
to the Snow Queen's palace.
All I have to do is agree to
attend some ball she's giving.
Perfect. That's where Chen
is putting on show.
What are you
thinking about?
Nothing.
Come on,
you can tell me.
Do you mind if I go
into the luggage room
to look for something?
There is no way out
from there.
I'm not looking
for a way out.
I just want
to find something.
What?
You'll see.
Here we are.
The peasant look
is so last year, darling.
It's light,
classic fabrics
and heavy jewels
at the moment.
A lot of money and plenty
of weight on fingers and face.
Look in the mirror,
pumpkin.
Mirrors don't lie.
Tell me what you see.
I don't know.
Nobody special.
Yes...
Well, that's what we're
going to change, darling.
Promise me one
thing, poppet.
Just don't leave
the grounds.
The woods are full
of the most terrible robbers;
I'd hate to see you become
yet another unfortunate victim.
Do I look a porker
in this dress?
I haven't got
time to change.
We have such
a full day ahead of us.
What are those men
doing outside?
They're queuing
for tickets, darling.
It's the engagement ball,
the biggest night of the summer.
All the eligible bachelors
will be there,
and if we're going
to get you married,
we have to make you
absolutely beautiful.
Married?
But I don't want
to be married.
I've told you,
I'm looking for Kai.
And I promised to tell you
where to find him,
but first you have
to check out the field,
to see how many wonderful
young men are waiting for you.
But, Princess,
it's Kai I love.
Only Kai.
Oh, yes.
That cute, coy thing you do—
that "little girl lost" look,
keep that.
It's very provocative.
You'll have
the men drooling.
"What a peach,
what a catch."
Trust me
on this one.
You'll be engaged
before midnight.
Just a minute!
Just a minute.
Wolfgang,
come downstairs.
You've got guests
to be seen to.
Why should I care,
minna?
Because you've got
a hotel to run,
and it's the best hotel in town.
Now, come on.
What's the point?
The point is...
The point is,
it's over, old friend.
I barely have the strength
to live anymore.
I can stand upright,
but that's about it.
All right, come on,
lean forward.
You have to lean
on one side of the skate.
Polar bears
don't do a lot of leaning.
Whoa!
Easy, I got you.
All right. Just try it.
Push forward.
Can you go a little faster?
Try to go a little faster.
Hey, I think I'm getting
the hang of it.
Watch this.
Easy!
Hello,
my name is Reginald.
I have an excellent pedigree,
and several university diplomas.
One of them is in dancing.
May I show you a few steps?
Summa cum laude
in the waltz...
And honorable mention
in the flamenco.
My other diplomas
include horsemanship,
sportsmanship...
And awfully
nice manners.
Oh, dear.
I thought he was your type.
Very nice
cheekbones,
and all those
diplomas...
But, Princess, I'm really
not looking for anybody,
no, of course.
You're a shy girl, aren't you?
Except that
shy girls
don't break into
palaces at night,
do they?
With wandering conjurers, hmm?
Oh— things
are looking up!
Eyes left, coming
straight towards us.
Get a load
of the dimples on this one.
Major delfont chalfont,
at your service.
I'd lay down my life
if your honor was at stake.
Would you like
to dance?
Thank you, but I'm really
not a dancer.
Neither am I, my darling,
but, do you know,
I like to put on
a rather good show.
Did I ever tell you
all about my exploits
with the 35th horse brigade
at the battle of tompkins bay?
You couldn't have.
We've only just met.
We were absolutely
surrounded, you know,
on all sides,
by these strapping
circassian warriors.
Great scimitars
flashing.
There was a cannon
to the left of us,
a cannon also
to the right of us.
Do you know what
my colonel said,
when he walked up
to me?
One of the most
amusing anecdotes
I think
I've ever heard...
How big
is this place?
As big as you
want it to be.
I think you've got
natural ability.
Do you really?
Or are you just buttering me up
before trying to escape again?
No, I'm simply
having fun.
All right,
as long as it's
just that.
I wouldn't be surprised
if she kissed me again tonight.
Let go, I didn't mean it!
I'm sorry!
I can't breathe!
You're in love with her
yourself, aren't you?
Just let me go.
Then it'd just be
you and her.
Please let me go.
I'm not meant to be here.
No.
I'm not going to hold out
much longer.
Please let me go home.
No.
No... no!
Why are you so angry?
Is it because you're in pain?
How long have you
been in pain?
Let me guess.
Since you met her,
perhaps?
I've been watching you
all evening, my darling,
and I'm head over heels
in love with you.
They call me
"handsome Helmut."
I'm sorry, Helmut,
I'm not in the mood for—
would you look at my profile
just for a moment?
Paying particular
attention to the angle
at which my nose
relates to my forehead.
Yes, they go together
very well.
Is that all
you have to say?
Are you aware that young ladies
generally lose consciousness
perhaps
they do, Helmut,
but I, for some reason,
am able to resist it.
She's not showing interest
in any of the men.
If she doesn't fall in love,
summer will come to an end.
Count rothstein,
go to her,
don't come back until
she's fallen in love with you.
I've tried twice already.
She just looks the other way.
All right.
This calls for real firepower.
Send in Charles D'Amour.
Charles D'Amour?
If anyone
can make her forget
about this silly little boy
she's doting on,
it's Charles D'Amour.
Come on.
Let's find him.
You leave me
no choice.
I'm going to
kill myself
unless you agree to marry me
this very moment.
Helmut...
That's it. It's over.
Hold these, would you?
I am...
Charles D'Amour,
Prince of Burgundy.
I have ridden bareback
from France to find beauty.
Mon amour,
my search is over.
Enchante.
Who are you?
I'm Chen the magician,
and lady has vanished.
Why, you little...
Conjurer has also vanished.
Good night.
Kai...
What's the word
to describe you?
Willful.
Willful would be
a good word.
You're testing
my patience.
I've been working really hard.
I just needed a break.
I mean,
I can't work forever.
Do you know what I think
the problem is?
Your mind
is on other things,
like that
silly little girl.
What's she like—
my rival?
Your kind of girl,
I bet.
Doe-eyed and obedient.
A little bit bland.
Please give it back to me.
It's all I've got.
It's all
you've got?
It's all you've got?
I laid out everything for you.
I pampered you, and that's
what you say to me?
Do you have any idea
how insulting that is?
Never mind.
I'm going away tomorrow
to start my work again,
bring a little snow
on the mountaintops,
remind people
winter's coming.
Give it back.
Come up and see me when you're
ready for that second kiss.
That was lovely.
Everybody,
wasn't it?
You... you watched
my dream?
Of course.
It was wonderful.
That's spying.
Didn't you watch my dreams
that first night?
And didn't you
promise me
you'd tell me where to find
the Snow Queen's palace?
And all you've done
is try to keep me here.
All the information
you need is here, dear,
and tonight,
it'll be yours.
No.
I have to find Kai.
But you have found him.
He's here, in your dreams,
whenever you wish,
and he'll always be perfect.
What could be
better than that?
This.
What you don't seem
to realize, dear,
is that i'm
quite serious
about finding
a husband for you.
Smart, beautiful assistant
wanting to leave palace?
Stay out of this,
conjurer.
It's no business
of yours.
Let's go.
Stop her!
Guards! Stop her!
Hey! Here I am.
There she is!
Forward!
This way!
Wow!
First time
that trick ever worked.
Thank you, Chen.
I'll never forget you.
I'm not sure the boy's going
to get the mirror finished,
not in time,
anyway.
Well, it's your job
to see that he does,
before the winter solstice.
Am I clear?
As ice.
I just don't see
why you're pinning
so much hope on this one.
Love.
True love.
Kai's seen it, felt it,
had it...
Has it.
He's not the only one.
What did you say?
Nothing.
Who are you?
The reason princesses
shouldn't go strolling about
alone in the forest,
my dear.
I'm not a Princess,
and I'll walk where I like,
thank you very much.
Get out of my way.
Oh, "get out
of my way," is it?
What do you think
about that, boys?
We think that's a bit
of a giggle, "robber girl."
Leave me alone.
Shut it, Princess.
You're coming with us.
Yes.
I'm the Summer Princess now.
Look at me.
What ransom
we're going to get.
Yes!
Come meet my mom.
Mom! The Princess
is here.
What have you
brought me today, girl?
Brought you
the Summer Princess.
What have you got
in your hand?
Give it
back to me.
Pretty—
but very sharp.
She's not
the Summer Princess.
She is!
She was in a complete
Summer Princess outfit.
She's right.
I'm just a poor, ordinary girl.
No one will pay
any ransom for me.
Might as well shove you
in the cooking pot, then.
Is the water boiling yet?
I've got quite a hunger
on me tonight.
She'll do just nicely.
And make sure
you add some onions!
The palace might pay something.
You never know.
You're not
cooking her.
What do you think you're doing?
That's my dinner.
No, I need a playmate.
There is no one
my own age to play with.
I always told you
not to play with your food.
Throw her in the pot.
I don't think I'll taste
that good... really.
I need
a peer group.
She's not a peer group.
She's supper.
So, can I keep her?
Do we have any rabbits?
Couple of sacks full.
All right,
you can have her.
We'll do a curry.
See if you can rustle up
some of that basmati rice.
There you are.
I didn't let them
kill you, did I?
If I get cross with you,
I'll do it myself.
Go on.
There's nothing to it.
Come on.
You must have robbed
a lot of people.
Oh, they deserved it.
The former owner of this hat
was a pompous twit.
That hat suits you.
I'm not sure if I believe
in stealing things...
Or killing people.
I don't believe in it, either.
I just do it.
Want an apple?
Don't worry,
I'll teach you
everything I know.
Then, when something
comes along in life
that you want,
you'll be able to take it,
just like that.
Come on,
time for bed.
I knew you'd be back.
Dance, damn you!
Come on, dance!
I want real dancing,
like...
The conga!
Yes, that's what I want!
She's getting uppity,
the robber girl.
There's nothing wrong
with my daughter.
She's a fine girl
in a fine robbing tradition.
She spat in your eye
today, didn't she?
Shows she's got
what it takes, that's all.
You're gonna
put up with that?
All right,
now through the fire,
not just around it.
Through the fire.
I trusted you.
I knew you'd
let me down.
Everyone does!
I ought to slit
your throat.
Exactly what I'd hoped
you'd say, girl.
You're growing up.
Go on, do it.
I ought to
cut off your head,
and use it
for a football.
That's the spirit.
Come on, lads, form two teams.
We're going
to have a game.
Teamwork, essence
of good robbing.
Want to borrow this?
Make a nice,
clean job of it?
No thank you, mom.
I have my own way
of dealing with this.
What are you going to do,
saw it off?
Good idea.
Teach her a lesson
she won't forget.
If you don't
want to be with me,
you can be in our jail.
I hate you!
You can rot there forever!
You've really
disappointed them,
you know that?
They were really looking forward
to a bit of clean, healthy fun,
and you've just spoiled it.
Tcha!
Anybody fancy
some mah-jongg?
Roulette?
Russian roulette?
Yeah!
Mr. Mayor, tell him
he can't do that.
What do you think
you're up to, Wolfgang?
I'm closing up
the white bear hotel,
that's what I'm up to.
But you can't, Wolfgang.
You can't do that.
I can.
I don't care if I
never see a guest
as long as I live.
But think of the town, Wolfgang.
Think what this means
to the town.
I don't care
about the town,
about this hotel,
and I don't care
about you...
Any of you.
Now, go away
and leave me alone.
Describe it.
I can't.
No, you can't.
Do you know what
winter is, Kai?
Winter is me.
What's happened
to me?
Everything looks
so perfect,
so mathematical.
I mean, look at this.
Perfect patterns,
perfect shapes.
It's nothing, Kai.
Even this,
everything you're feeling
in this moment,
this is just a snowflake
on an iceberg.
This is just the start
of your change.
We're at the end
of the world, Kai.
No one could
ever come here.
Just you and me.
Kiss me again.
I'm ready.
Would you like to ride
a storm with me?
on the wind and the snow?
You know what you could do,
now that you can see like this?
Tell me.
I'll do anything.
You can finish
the little mirror puzzle.
I bet you could do it in a month
if you didn't sleep.
A month?
I could stay awake
for a year.
I've told you
a thousand times,
you don't actually have
to Rob on your first time.
You can just watch.
No.
Why not?
They'd kill us,
given half the chance.
How do you think I got his?
Shot at, I was.
No, you weren't.
I've seen you
without your eye patch.
There's nothing wrong
with your eye.
But I might
have been shot at.
Except that you
shot at them first?
Exactly.
I'm not going to go out
shooting at people,
just in case they shoot at me,
and wearing an eye patch
to make people
feel sorry for me.
What about the benefits?
I mean, the proceeds?
Well, I'm sorry.
I'm not going to be a robber,
and that's that.
I have to find Kai.
The boy?
The boy who left you?
He didn't leave me.
The Snow Queen took him.
She didn't take him.
He left.
He went off with another woman.
An older woman at that.
Trailing on after him,
like a lovesick calf?
I have to rescue him.
How do you know
he wants rescuing?
Because I love him.
Because he loves me.
If he loves you,
then why did he go off with her?
She hardened his heart.
And you think you can
soften it, do you?
I will try.
Have you any idea how powerful
the Snow Queen really is?
Have you any idea how cruel,
and cold, and wonderful
she can be?
How can you even think
you can stand up to her?
Because I love him,
that's why.
With all my heart.
Well, you're kidding yourself,
and I'm going to make sure
you stop kidding yourself,
and you stay here
until you see sense,
and take up a useful career,
like robbing.
Do we have to
just tap,
or can we talk
as well?
Who's in there?
I'm rutger.
Who are you?
Gerda.
Are you in a cell as well?
No. I'm in a shed.
I can see the daylight.
I could escape,
if only I wasn't
chained to the wall.
How long have you
been in there?
I'm not sure.
I think about two years.
No...
Oh, yes. Once they catch you,
they never let you go.
If only I could
get to you...
You could unchain me,
and then we can get out.
I could kick
the door down.
Kick your way out?
Do you really think so?
Well, we have to look
on the bright side,
don't we?
They're all different.
That's the amazing thing.
Why did I have trouble
distinguishing between them?
Each one of them
has its own personality.
I can see the patterns.
I can see the patterns
before my eyes.
Oh, I meant
to ask you,
do you remember that girl
you used to talk about?
I do, yes.
You're sure?
Yes.
Remind me...
What did she look like?
I wouldn't call her ugly,
but, a boy like you,
you're one in a million.
You deserve the best.
And that's you.
Why don't you show him
the others?
You don't want him
to like me, bear?
Well?
You know I don't.
And why would that be?
You know the answer to that,
as well.
But I like to hear it.
Be— because
I love you.
What was that?
I didn't quite catch that.
Because
I love you.
Because you love me.
How wonderfully absurd.
He loves me.
You're not like the other boys,
are you, Kai?
Not at all.
They were
just pieces.
She's gotten
far too big for her boots.
She needs taking down
a peg or two,
before the whole year
is covered with snow.
All my frozen
failures.
There's magic in this.
I want to know about it.
It was my mother's,
and now it's mine.
It's mine.
You've got it,
but it's not yours,
and it never will be.
Is that so?
It's the only thing I have
of hers, and she's dead,
so I think you should
give it back to me.
People die
all the time.
They blaze red
as if they're going
to live forever,
but they all fall
sooner or later.
There's nothing
you can do about it.
People don't come back
because we want them to...
Princess.
The world moves on.
Even I can't stop the leaves
from falling.
I know she won't
come back,
but I just want to keep
a piece of her with me.
Wouldn't you want your daughter
to keep hold
of something of yours
when you're gone?
There's heat
in this brooch.
That's what she fears,
you know.
The one you want to see.
The one who's got your man.
Do you know her?
Know her?
She's my sister.
But...
But she's a queen.
And I'm just
a robber, eh?
It shouldn't be like that,
should it?
Is it right?
Is it just?
Of course it isn't.
She's gotten far too powerful.
Yes.
She needs taking down
a peg or two.
But your daughter
said I wasn't strong enough.
What does she know?
Will you let me go?
Will you let me go find her,
so I can go save Kai?
You are no threat
to her.
But she'd never
forgive me.
Who, the robber girl?
Of course she will—
you're her mother.
You think girls
ever forgive their mothers?
Of course not.
Please help me, mother.
Please help me to find Kai,
and get him back.
Keep going,
keep going.
I can see
the wall buckling.
It's hard.
I know it's hard,
but believe me,
when you're through,
it'll be worth it.
Who's that?
Who are you talking to?
Myself.
I'm talking to myself
because I'm lonely.
You can come out
whenever you want,
as soon as you agree
to join the band.
No!
Fine.
Stay there and rot.
We're having
paella tonight,
and you're not going
to get any.
Stolen paella.
Still tastes
delicious, though.
Let me know
when you want to come out,
and you can get some.
Well, hello.
I... I thought
you were a person.
No, more
of a reindeer, really.
It's the antlers,
you know.
You wouldn't by any chance
have any acorns on you, hmm?
Is anyone going to do anything
about breakfast?
Hey, watch your head.
Watch your head!
Winter's almost here.
I can see the snow
on top of the hills.
Good for sledging.
Wonderful,
having hands.
Hooves aren't much use
for that kind of thing.
No, but they'll be good
to race away from here
faster than the wind,
when we get out of here.
Do you know the way
to lapland?
Lapland?
Like the back of my antlers.
I need to find the Snow Queen
before the winter solstice.
Yes, I think I can
get you there in time.
I think we should run through
huge zigzags through the forest,
so the robbers won't know
which way we're going to go.
Zigzags, yes,
but not the running, of course,
not at my age.
Have you ever had arthritis?
But why did I spend
all of this effort,
digging through
this wall if—
there was
just a poor old reindeer
on the other side,
hoping you'd help him?
I'm sorry.
That was very selfish of me.
I'm very glad to have
met you, rutger
even if you do have
some... mobility problems.
How very touching.
Uh-oh!
You were about to steal
my reindeer.
Not too many scruples
about robbing
when it comes to something
you actually want, huh?
This is completely
different.
In fact, if you think
robbing's so fine,
you'll have no problem
with me robbing you.
Ooh— saucy.
Well take that, saucy girl.
Nobody steals
from the robber girl,
and nobody gets away
or they feel... this.
Or not, depending
on the reindeer.
What do you think you're doing,
you rheumatic old fool?
Fighting for freedom.
What do you think
you're doing?
What you taught me to do,
robber girl.
Standing up for myself.
Standing up
for yourself?
Yes. You only think
about what you want,
and now I'm going to think
about what I want,
and that's to get out
of here, and find Kai.
Mommy!
Faster, rutger.
This is faster.
Clever boy.
No one's ever gotten close
to what you've done.
I knew when I first saw you
that you were special.
It's magnificent,
and I applaud you.
To come so close...
What do you mean, "so close"?
It's complete.
I've done what you've
asked me to do.
Maybe there's something
wrong with my eyesight,
but there seems to be
one piece missing.
Where is it?
I've looked everywhere.
You've hidden it from me,
haven't you?
Because that's all there is,
all right? It's not there.
You're not quite ready
for that last kiss.
You haven't
worked it out yet.
It's not here.
I've looked
for three days.
I've crawled
on my hands and knees.
I can see everything
in this room,
every tiny speck.
It's not here.
It is here.
It's not!
Why can't I finish
the puzzle?
You're not going
to like the answer.
Listen.
What?
The story
is being told.
Can you hear it
on the wind?
Thousands and thousands
of years ago,
deep down in hell...
The devil
made a mirror.
The devil gave this
beautiful mirror
to the four seasons,
so that they could
admire their work,
and when the spring
stood in front of the mirror,
it reflected the essence
of her season,
and the promise of life.
And so it was for summer...
And autumn.
And when the winter
stood in front of the mirror,
the world was reflected
cold and covered in snow,
and that was
as it should be,
for each season
has its power and its time,
and there was harmony.
But the devil
had made the mirror twisted,
so that as winter gazed
at her own face,
she longed to be queen
of the seasons,
and one day
she stole the mirror,
and took it to the arctic
wastes for herself.
Now she was
the Snow Queen,
and the world
became a colder place,
but not cold
enough for her,
because autumn, and spring,
and summer still existed,
however diminished,
so she took the mirror,
and flew with it
up into the sky
that winter should rule
the earth, unchallenged.
But as she
approached heaven,
the mirror
shook and shook,
as if good and evil
were wrestling
for control.
When the pieces
fell to earth,
and flew round
and round,
until they flew
into people's eyes—
when those people
looked at the world,
they saw it as cold
and ugly,
and each winter,
she began to roam the earth,
looking for all
the missing pieces,
that one day she'd be able
to put the mirror back together,
and again become
all-powerful.
So you see why you can't
finish the puzzle?
Hmm?
Kai?
Kai, are you
all right?
It's inside me.
I'm
the missing piece.
How can I ever leave,
if I can't complete the mirror?
You can't.
How do I get it
out of me?
Just one
last kiss.
We're too late.
I'm never
going to be able
to get you there
in time.
Yes, you can,
I know it.
Gerda, I'm sorry.
I'm just... too old.
It's just over
those mountains.
Do you think you can
get there without me?
Nothing's going to stop me,
rutger.
So long, Gerda.
No, please.
Please what?
"Please don't kill me"?
No. Please let me
take Kai away.
Why should I do that?
Because I love him.
Why should I care
about that?
Don't you love
anybody?
Kai?
Kai!
Kai...
Who are you?
What's happened to you?
What's happened
to your eyes?
You must remember me.
You must.
Please go,
before she finds you here.
No...
I've come to take you
home with me.
You must remember me.
I'm sorry, I don't seem
to know anything anymore.
Those boots...
I know those boots.
Yes.
I bought them.
Yes, yes, you did.
For you.
Gerda.
Yes.
I gave up hope.
What's wrong?
I feel so cold.
Where are you?
Stop doing this!
Please don't tell me
you thought
I'd let her just
come in here and take you,
because that would be such
an insult to my intelligence.
Stop it. She's dying.
I will stop,
and I'll let her live.
All you have to do
is kiss me a third time.
No.
I don't want her.
I want you.
What's more
important, Kai?
Your life
or hers?
One kiss from me
and she'll live.
Take all the time you want,
even though she's dying.
She's going, Kai...
Just like
her poor mother.
How well I remember
her last breath.
I'll do it.
Just don't kill her.
I knew you would.
Let the whole world
be as I am.
Let winter
rule always.
Wake up.
Wake up, sleepy girl,
wake up.
Wake up.
Come on, darling.
Come on, wake up!
Wake up!
You know what to do.
Wake up.
Mommy's dead.
Get up, darling.
Mommy.
It's all right.
You don't have to cry
for me anymore.
It's time to move on.
You can do it.
What are you doing?
I froze you.
Oh, so you think
you're strong enough?
Such a fool.
Did you really think
you could take Kai away from me?
I'm the Snow Queen.
You're not
the Snow Queen.
You're just winter...
And winter passes.
It passes.
Kai, Kai...
I love you, Kai.
I love you.
What did you say?
That's what
I thought it was.
Help me. Help me.
I can't stand.
It's all right.
I'm here.
Come on.
Gerda! Kai!
You came back.
I knew you would,
I knew you would.
Minna, it's so good
to see you again.
Where's Daddy?
Minna,
what happened?
Go away,
whoever you are.
Leave me alone.
I've told you often enough.
Daddy?
It's me, Gerda.
Not true.
Yes, Daddy,
it's true. I'm back.
Gerda!
I found Kai,
Daddy.
He's come back
with me.
We're never going to part
from one another again.
Tardiness of any
shape or form
will not be tolerated.
Now, get on with you!
Get!